[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[Se deben proteger las obras originales]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[Fragancia Eterna]
[Episode 20]
[Episodio 20]
Qin.
Qin.
What happened to you?
¿Qué te pasó?
Did you get beaten up in your dream?
¿Alguien te golpeó en tu sueño?
I'm fine.
Estoy bien.
Trouble!
¡Algo va mal!
Demons are breaking the mountain-sea barrier.
Los demonios están atacando la barrera de Montañas y Mares.
Return to the city at once
¡Vuelvan a la ciudad ahora
and guard the people.
para protejar al pueblo!
The demon beast Qiongqi.
¡Bestia demoníaca, Qiongqi!
[Qiongqi] I'm Qiongqi. Greetings, My Lord.
[Qiongqi] Saludos, Su Excelencia.
My Lord,
Su Excelencia,
you've finally returned.
por fin ha regresado.
Is the lord you mentioned
¿El que llamas excelencia
the Demon Lord Yecha?
es el Rey Demonio Yaksha?
Word spread that you reappeared on the White Cliff.
Cuando supe que Su Excelencia apareció en el Acantilado Baibian,
The whole demon clan
todos los demonios
longs for your arrival.
estaban esperando su regreso.
After five centuries of exile and humiliation,
500 años de humillación y sufrimiento,
we've dreamed of your return
hemos soñado con que usted volviera
to restore our demon clan.
para restaurar la Raza Demoníaca.
I'm not your Demon Lord.
Yo no soy su rey.
Leave Duanming City
Tomen a sus subordinados
with your followers at once.
y salgan de la Ciudad Duanming ahora mismo.
But the Guardians ordered...
Pero el guardián ordenó...
Yes, My Lord.
¡A su orden!
Thank you.
Gracias.
Tongzhou.
Tongzhou.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Uncle.
Tío.
What's this?
¿Qué es esto?
The Four Symbols Divine Fire Formation.
La Formación del Fuego de Cuatro Direcciones.
Medicine.
Tráeme la medicina.
Here.
Venga, toma.
Are you alright?
¿Estás bien?
I'm fine.
Estoy bien.
Move!
¡Rápido!
Get up!
¡Arriba!
Get up right now, you beast!
¡Arriba, bestia!
Are you seeking death?
¿Quieres morir?
- Get up. - Are you hurt?
Levántate, ¿estás bien?
Who's there?
¿Quién es?
It's just a cub.
Solo es una cría.
Doesn't seem to have killed anyone.
No parece que haya matado a nadie.
Why slay it?
¿Por qué matarla?
You
Tú eres la bruja que liberó
spared that little beast last time!
al pequeño demonio la última vez.
You...
¡Tú!
All of you
¡Ustedes!
are in league with the monster beast.
Conspiraron con los demonios.
Bully the weak
Oprimir a los débiles
and twist the truth, huh?
y encima echar la culpa a otros, ¿no?
Duanming City used to live in peace.
Nuestra ciudad siempre ha estado en paz.
Ever since you showed up,
Desde que llegaron ustedes,
either the barrier breaks
o la barrera falló,
or demon beasts run amok.
o los demonios causaron problemas.
How can you deny you're spies?
¿Y aún niegan que son espías?
What do you mean?
¿Qué quiere decir con desde que llegamos?
We've worked tirelessly
Nos esforzamos tanto
to subdue monsters and calm chaos.
en eliminar demonios y restaurar el orden,
How dare you slander us?
¿y nos acusa injustamente?
Everyone knows Mountain Sect's disciples are crafty.
Todos sabemos que los discípulos de la Secta del Mar son tramposos.
Chances are, you came to the East Sea
Seguro que vinieron al Mar del Este
with malicious intent to stir trouble.
con malas intenciones para traernos problemas.
Watch your words!
¿Cómo te atreves a hablar así?
You slander us out of thin air!
¿Nos están difamando?
This is the Sea Sect's territory.
Este es territorio de nuestra Secta del Mar.
Leave at once!
¡Lárguense!
Silence!
¡Cállense todos!
Among these captured monster beasts,
Entre estos demonios capturados,
some are spirit companions raised by the Sea Sect.
algunos son mascotas entrenadas por la Secta del Mar.
There is a hidden truth behind this chaos.
El motín tiene otra causa.
The Guangsheng Faction only detains them,
La Sociedad Guangsheng solo los retiene,
with no authority to pass judgment.
no tiene derecho a decidir su destino.
Mr. Shen and the immortal elders haven't looked into this yet.
El Sr. Shen y los maestros de las sectas aún no han intervenido.
You're trying to kill them to cover up the truth, huh?
Creo que quieren matar a los demonios para silenciarlos.
Fine, forget it.
Bueno, bueno, ya.
Let's go.
Vámonos, vámonos.
Come.
Venga.
Go.
Vamos.
Hurry up!
¡Rápido!
Be careful.
Despacio.
Behave yourselves.
¡Todos quietos!
Hurry.
¡Rápido!
I'll follow them to watch them,
Los seguiré para que
in case they stir up more trouble.
no vuelvan a causar problemas.
[Duanming City Inn]
[Posada de Ciudad Duanming]
You know that cultivating the Xuanhua Sacred Fire
Sabes bien que practicar el Fuego Sagrado Xuanhua
requires severing all mortal affection.
requiere renunciar al amor y al deseo.
Yet only a few days after arriving in Duanming City,
Y en pocos días en la Ciudad Duanming,
your spirit sense has sustained damage,
tu conciencia espiritual ya está dañada,
and a heart tribulation looms over you.
como si hubieras caído en una prueba del corazón.
Is it because of Jiang Lifei?
¿Es por esa Jiang Lifei?
I let my guard down for a moment.
Fue un descuido mío.
It has nothing to do with her.
Lifei no tiene nada que ver con eso.
Besides, she's far stronger now.
Además, ella ya no es la de antes,
Her cultivation has advanced greatly,
su nivel ha mejorado mucho
and she saved me on Fanghu Island.
y me salvó en la Isla Fanghu.
Tongzhou,
Tongzhou,
the Xuanhua Sacred Fire is the Hua Sect's supreme technique.
el Fuego Sagrado Xuanhua es la técnica más alta de la Secta Hua.
No one has mastered it in hundreds of years,
En cientos de años, nadie ha logrado dominarla,
not even me.
ni siquiera yo.
If you cannot cast aside personal desires
Si no puedes cortar tus deseos personales
and master the Sacred Fire,
y dominar el fuego sagrado,
how will you lead Xingzheng Hall
¿cómo vas a liderar el Pabellón Xingzheng
and fulfill the grand plan to secure Yue's realm?
y cumplir con el plan del Reino Yue?
I'll master the supreme technique.
Dominaré el Fuego Sagrado Xuanhua.
You have my word.
Tío, no se preocupe.
But
Pero
I'll never give up Jiang Lifei.
tampoco voy a renunciar a Jiang Lifei.
In your life,
En la vida,
you gain only after you let go.
hay que perder para ganar.
The immortal path is lonely.
El gran camino es solitario.
How can you have both?
¿Cómo se pueden tener todo a la vez?
Whether I can have both,
Si puedo tener todo,
I'll have my own judgment.
yo mismo lo decidiré.
No need to lecture me
Tío, no necesita repetírmelo
over and over.
una y otra vez.
Very well.
Bien.
If you insist on this foolish path,
Ya que insistes en ser tan terco,
so be it.
está bien.
I'll wait for the day you hit a dead end
Esperaré a que llegues al callejón sin salida
and damage your cultivation.
y arruines tu cultivo.
Tongzhou,
Tongzhou.
here's the antidote to the monster poison...
La medicina para el veneno demoníaco...
Mr. Xuanshan.
Maestro Xuanshan.
He's so furious.
Está de mal humor.
Still because of the mirage dream?
¿Es por el hechizo onírico?
What did you see?
¿Qué viste?
Are you still under its influence?
¿Todavía te afecta?
All those illusions are fake.
Esas ilusiones son falsas.
Dwelling on them, and you'll lose yourself.
Si piensas demasiado en ellas, te pierdes.
I'm not dwelling on it.
No pienso en ellas.
You don't understand.
No entiendes.
Don't understand?
¿No entiendo?
Because I don't dwell on painful memories.
Es porque no quiero aferrarme a cosas malas.
Dreams show the opposite of reality.
Los sueños son al revés.
Try to look on the bright side,
Si lo ves desde otro ángulo,
and they might be a good sign.
quizá sea algo bueno.
A good sign?
¿Bueno?
Think about it.
Piénsalo,
The illusion laid out
en la ilusión,
all your deepest fears,
supiste lo que temes.
so you can avoid them in the real world.
Así que en la realidad puedes evitarlo.
At the very least,
Al menos
you won't feel as helpless as you did in the illusion.
no estarás tan indefenso como en la ilusión.
Lifei,
Lifei,
if one day a great disaster befalls me,
si algún día me pasara una gran desgracia,
or
o si
I lose everything
perdiera todo
and am left all alone,
y me quedara sin nada,
would you abandon me?
¿me abandonarías?
Your Highness, do not abandon us,
Príncipe, no abandone
your friends.
a sus amigos.
How's Tongzhou?
¿Cómo está Tongzhou?
He's alright,
Está bien.
just acting a little strange.
Solo que está un poco raro.
Probably the mirage dream scared him badly.
Quizá el hechizo onírico fue demasiado terrible.
By the way,
Por cierto,
did you catch demon beast Qiongqi?
¿atrapaste a la bestia demoníaca Qiongqi?
It got away.
Se escapó.
If it escaped your grasp,
¿Se escapó de ti?
it must be extremely powerful.
Entonces es un rival poderoso.
I wonder how many demon beasts are in the city.
No se sabe cuántos demonios más se han infiltrado en la ciudad.
You are fiery
Tienes un temperamento ardiente
and passionate.
y eres apasionado.
Your cultivation
Tu cultivo
will surely be fraught with hardships.
será muy difícil.
All love, hatred, grudges, entanglements,
Todo el amor, el odio, los sentimientos,
and the bustling mortal world
todos los vínculos mundanos,
will stoke an unquenchable inner flame.
el fuego del corazón es difícil de apagar.
If you cannot let go,
Si no puedes trascenderlo,
how can you make progress?
¿cómo vas a progresar?
Tongzhou.
Tongzhou.
Lifei.
Lifei.
Dwelling on them,
Si piensas demasiado en ello,
and you'll lose yourself.
te perderás.
It is a fleeting dream,
Solo fue un sueño.
all fake.
Todo es falso.
Let it go.
Olvídalo.
Lifei.
Lifei.
Speak!
¡Habla!
Who ordered you to stir up trouble?
¿Quién les ordenó causar disturbios?
You humans are selfish and hypocritical.
Ustedes, los humanos, son egoístas e hipócritas,
You oppress the monster clan
oprimen a la raza demoníaca
and slaughter us at will.
y la masacran sin piedad.
We only fled for our lives.
Solo huimos para sobrevivir.
What's wrong with that?
¿Qué culpa tenemos?
So it's possessed by the demon clan.
Resulta que fue poseído por un demonio.
Speak!
¡Habla!
Monster,
¡Demonio!
who is your demon leader?
¿Quién es su líder?
Old fool.
¡Maldito!
The Demon Lord has returned.
El Rey Demonio ha regresado.
The Guardians' schemes are flawless.
El guardián lo calculó todo.
Soon we'll conquer the Central Plains
Pronto arrasarán las Tierras Centrales
and slay every last one of you.
y los aniquilarán a todos.
Which Guardian?
¿Qué guardián?
Are they hiding in the city now?
¿Todavía está escondido en la ciudad?
Five centuries ago,
Hace 500 años,
I fought two Guardians of the demon clan.
me enfrenté a los dos guardianes de los demonios.
They were extremely crafty.
Son muy astutos.
Whichever one has sneaked in,
Cualquiera de ellos que se haya infiltrado
they will prove a deadly foe.
será un enemigo terrible.
Mr. Shen,
Sr. Shen,
we can't question every
no podemos interrogar a cada bestia
captured monster beast.
que capturamos.
In my opinion,
Propongo que
we may execute all of them together
las ejecutemos a todas
to eliminate future threats.
para erradicar el problema.
Lifei!
¡Lifei!
It's terrible!
¡Mala noticia!
Elder Cuixuan has ordered
El maestro Cuixuan ordenó
that all captured monster beasts must be killed.
ejecutar a todas las bestias.
Did they find the demon leader?
¿Encontraron al líder demoníaco?
Why kill the monster clan suddenly?
¿Por qué de repente quieren matar a las bestias?
Last night, I went to the Guangsheng Faction's prison
Anoche fui a la prisión de la Sociedad Guangsheng,
to make sure they wouldn't kill the spirits.
me aseguré de que no mataran a los espíritus.
But when I came back this morning,
Pero esta mañana,
Luo Chengji's disciples passed down the order
los discípulos de Luo Chengji dieron la orden de
to transfer all monster beasts to the shore
llevar a todas las bestias espirituales a la costa
and kill them all,
para ejecutarlas
none spared.
sin excepción.
Deng,
Deng,
what are you doing?
¿qué quieres hacer?
Step out here!
¡Afuera!
You're hiding a spirit right under the elder's nose.
¿Están escondiendo espíritus bajo la nariz del maestro?
Are you seeking death?
¿Están locos?
I saved this little one before.
Este es un pequeño espíritu que salvé antes.
It risked its life to save me yesterday
Ayer me salvó la vida
and is sharing key information with us.
y tiene algo importante que decirnos.
That day, after Lifei saved me,
Después de que Lifei me salvó,
I planned to head back
quería volver con mis tíos
to my homeland, Yingcui Island, with my elders.
a mi hogar, la Isla Yingcui.
But before we left the city,
Pero antes de salir de la ciudad,
all the spirit beasts around suddenly went berserk,
las bestias espirituales a mi alrededor de repente se volvieron locas.
and my elders lost their minds too.
Mis tíos también enloquecieron.
I tried to hold them back,
Quise detenerlos,
yet they acted as if they didn't know me
pero parecía que no me reconocían
and even tried to kill me.
y querían matarme.
Terrified,
Tuve miedo
I hid myself away,
y me escondí.
and that's when I met Lifei.
Luego me encontré con Lifei.
Spirit companions may have faint power,
Aunque las mascotas espirituales no son muy poderosas,
yet they possess some cultivation.
tienen algo de cultivo.
Why are they controlled by the demon clan so easily?
¿Cómo pudieron ser controlados tan fácilmente por los demonios?
Before they lost control,
Antes del incidente,
did you eat or drink anything?
¿comieron o bebieron algo?
To avoid being captured again by the Guangsheng Faction,
Teníamos miedo de que la Sociedad Guangsheng nos atrapara,
we didn't even have time to eat.
no comimos nada.
They drank water from a pond along the way.
Solo bebimos agua de un estanque.
I had a mouth wound
Yo tengo una herida en los labios,
and dared not touch the water.
no pude beber.
Now it all makes sense.
Ahí está.
I was wondering
Sabía que
how the demon clan could seize
no era posible que en una noche,
all the monster beasts in the city overnight
bajo la nariz de los maestros,
under the immortal elders' noses.
los demonios controlaran a todos los espíritus de la ciudad.
That would only alert us.
Eso sería alertar al enemigo.
There's only one explanation.
Solo hay una posibilidad.
The water source is poisoned.
Envenenaron el agua.
Yeah, they poisoned the water supply.
Sí, envenenaron el agua.
I've asked Gelin.
Pregunté a Gelin.
All underground water in Duanming City
Toda el agua subterránea de la Ciudad Duanming está conectada
connects to this freshwater lake.
y viene de este lago de agua dulce.
If someone wants to poison the water,
Si iban a envenenar,
this place will be the perfect spot.
este es el mejor lugar.
They're from the Guangsheng Faction.
Son de la Sociedad Guangsheng.
Mr. Shi,
Sr. Shi,
I've spread all the sea salt.
ya esparcí toda la sal marina.
After killing every monster beast tomorrow morning,
Solo esperamos a que maten a todas las bestias mañana.
we'll strip their hides
Las despellejaremos y
and cure their flesh.
las marinaremos.
Not a single hair will go to waste, I promise you.
No desperdiciaremos ni un pelo.
Seems that the man told me the truth.
Parece que ese tipo no me mintió.
Wait till you return to tally your gold.
Volvamos a contar la plata.
Let's go.
Vamos.
What if
Sr. Shi.
that old fool changes his mind
¿y si el viejo se arrepiente
and calls off the slaughter?
y no las mata?
He won't.
Imposible.
The immortal sects mean to bait someone out,
Las sectas quieren sacar al enemigo.
so they'll kill without mercy.
Están decididos a hacer la masacre.
Hurry, let's go.
¡Vamos, rápido!
Spirit-Releasing Antidote Powder.
Es Polvo Desintoxicante de Liberación Espiritual.
It's Shi Chengtian's doing, just as expected.
Fue Shi Chengtian quien movía los hilos.
I'm going to Mr. Shen.
Voy a buscar al Sr. Shen.
Don't bother.
No vayas.
To them,
Para ellos,
the truth means nothing.
la verdad no importa.
The elders know full well what caused
Las bestias perdieron el control,
the monster beasts to lose control.
¿crees que los maestros no saben?
They're using it to eliminate all non-human creatures
Solo usan esto como excusa para eliminar a las razas distintas
and future threats for good.
y acabar con el problema.
All lives are precious.
La vida es valiosa.
They have no right to decide
No tienen derecho a decidir
the fate of these innocent monster beasts.
la vida de esas bestias espirituales inocentes.
As the monster beasts ran amok,
Las bestias causaron disturbios.
slaying them is what everyone wants.
Matarlas es lo que la gente quiere.
If you speak up for them,
Si estás a favor de ellas,
be ready
debes estar dispuesta
to openly stand against the immortal sects.
a ponerte en contra a las sectas.
Do you understand?
¿Entiendes?
I do.
Entiendo.
At worst, I'll be barred from returning to Wuyue Court.
A lo sumo no podré volver a la Secta Wuyueting.
If they can't tell right from wrong
Si de verdad son tan injustos
and kill the innocent,
y matan inocentes sin escrúpulos,
I won't care to remain their disciple.
entonces no quiero ser discípula de las sectas.
In that case,
En aquel entonces,
we can return to the Chufeng Academy.
podemos volver a la Academia Chufeng.
Master...
Maestro...
Mr. Hu
Sr. Hu,
and Mr. Zuo Qiu will take us in.
o el rector Zuo Qiu nos acogerán.
Lifei,
¡Lifei!
count me in, too!
¡Cuenta conmigo!
Don't get mixed up in this.
No te metas.
How can I be your senior
Si no me meto,
and stand aside?
no soy tu compañero.
Besides, what are you off to do?
Y ustedes van a hacer algo grande:
Save all living beings!
¡salvar vidas!
It's such a meritorious deed.
¡Qué mérito tan grande!
I might even ascend to immortality from this.
Quizá hasta me vuelva inmortal por esta actividad.
You must count me in.
Tienen que llevarme.
This journey will be dangerous,
Este viaje es peligroso.
so you may back out at any time
Si se arrepienten,
if you regret it.
pueden retirarse.
- I'll never regret it.
- No me arrepiento. - No me arrepiento.
Everyone, good work out there.
Gracias a todos por su esfuerzo.
Mr. Shi sends his regards.
El Sr. Shi les manda saludos.
It didn't work at all.
No funciona.
I knew it.
Lo sabía,
Mr. Dongyang refined
el maestro Dongyang
this drug from sleep-inducing bugs,
hizo la medicina de gusanos dormilones,
so it can knock them all out.
seguro que los iba a derribar.
Go.
Vamos.
Wuyue Court's restriction spell.
¡Barrera de la Secta Wuyueting!
What do we do now?
¿Qué hacemos?
I know how to break it.
Yo sé romperla.
Then...
Bueno.
All arts converge as one;
¡Todos los caminos vuelven a uno!
break the formation and reveal the spirit.
¡Rompe la barrera y aparecen los espíritus!
You've got real skill.
¡Qué capaz eres!
Naturally.
Claro.
Since I was taken as my master's personal disciple at three,
Mi maestro me aceptó como discípulo directo cuando tenía tres años.
I've tinkered with these formations for over a decade.
Llevo más de diez años haciendo esto.
Child's play for me.
Es un pan comido para mí.
Let's go.
Vamos.
As the mirage poison lingers in your body for ages,
Llevas demasiado tiempo con el veneno del espejismo.
your spirit roots are damaged now.
Tu raíz espiritual está dañada.
It may take a decade
Para recuperarla,
to fully mend them.
necesitarás al menos diez años.
Darn it.
¡Maldición!
I'm incompetent
Soy inútil.
and have troubled you greatly.
Lo molesto, maestro.
Focus solely on recuperating for now.
Ahora solo reposa.
Once we return,
Cuando volvamos,
I'll have Dongyang tend to your conditioning carefully.
pediré a Dongyang que te dé un tratamiento.
Thank you, Master.
Gracias, maestro.
Master,
Maestro,
during our time on Fanghu Island,
en la Isla Fanghu,
I discovered that Jiang Lifei...
descubrí que Jiang Lifei...
There's a jailbreak rescue!
¡Alguien está asaltando la prisión!
Halt!
¡Alto!
You should guard the outside.
Ustedes se encargan de vigilar afuera.
Why have you come in?
¿Por qué entraron?
Any more drugs left?
¿Queda medicina?
I've given you all of it.
Ya te di toda.
I came inside to relieve myself
Tenía ganas de orinar, entré al baño.
and will head out right away.
Ya me voy.
- You... - He's far too strong.
- Tú... - El enemigo es muy fuerte.
I'll fetch reinforcements. Hold him off.
Voy a buscar ayuda, aguanta.
What a fair-weather friend.
¡Desleal!
Are you also here to relieve yourself?
¿Tú también viniste al baño?
I came along with him. I'm leaving.
Vine con él. Ya me voy.
Jiang Lifei.
Jiang Lifei.
You have sharp eyes and saw
¡Maestro, qué vista tan aguda!
right through my disguise at once.
Reconoció mi disfraz al instante.
Why are you dressed like this?
¿Por qué te vistes así?
I heard the monster beast chaos
Oí que los disturbios de los demonios
was stirred up by demon spies.
fueron obra de un espía demoníaco.
So I thought
Pensé que
if I dressed like this,
si me disfrazaba así,
I could capture and question a monster beast,
podría atrapar a alguna bestia y preguntarle.
so I could help you capture
Así podría ayudarlo
demon spies ahead of time.
a atrapar al espía antes.
She is cunning and will become a grave threat.
Esta mujer es astuta. En el futuro será un gran problema.
He's trying to kill me!
Quiere matarme.
I... I have
Yo... yo...
a terrible stomachache.
Me duele mucho la barriga.
May I step aside for a moment?
Necesito ir al baño.
Stomachache?
¿Dolor de barriga?
Then let me check your pulse.
Entonces te tomaré el pulso.
I'm sacrificing myself to save them!
Esto es morir por el plan.
Xiuyuan, everything rests on you.
Xiuyuan, todo depende de ti.
Lu.
¡Lu!
Clan leader.
¡Líder!
Clan leader?
¿Líder?
I'm a half-monster.
Soy medio humano y media bestia.
They are my clansfolk.
Estos son de mi clan.
I never thought disciples of the immortal sects
Nunca imaginé que todavía haya discípulos de las sectas
would lend a hand to the monster clan.
dispuestos a ayudar a mi raza.
Lei,
Lei.
thank you.
Gracias.
The elders will find out soon.
Los maestros pronto lo descubrirán.
We have to leave at once.
Tenemos que irnos rápido.
I'm at my limit.
No aguanto más.
I'll risk everything!
¡A dar todo!
An empty shell.
¿Un ataque simulado?
You were testing me.
¿Me estás probando?
You've got some perseverance.
Tienes algo de voluntad.
So you really came to rescue them.
¿Pero sí viniste a liberar prisioneros?
Uncle!
¡Tío!
Tongzhou?
¿Tongzhou?
Uncle,
Tío.
this whole thing was my idea.
Todo fue idea mía.
I told Lifei to...
Yo le pedí a Lifei...
To meet you.
¡A ver a usted!
Since His Highness is here,
Ya que el príncipe está aquí,
I'll speak plainly.
voy a decir la verdad.
What are you doing?
¿Qué haces?
Since His Highness got injured yesterday,
Después de lastimar al príncipe ayer,
I've been consumed with guilt.
no he dejado de sentir culpa.
I feared you'd hold a grudge against me.
Temía que usted se enojara conmigo.
But His Highness said
Pero el príncipe dijo
you're the kindest,
que usted es su tío amable
and you won't hold this against me.
y que no se enfadaría conmigo.
So I ventured here
Así que vine a arriesgarme
to explain myself.
para explicarle.
Uncle,
Tío,
please allow us to be cultivation partners.
le pido que me permita tomar a Lifei como novia de cultivo.
Lifei,
Lifei,
we've sworn to never abandon one another.
ya nos hicimos la promesa de no separarnos nunca.
My uncle won't make things hard for you.
Mi tío no te hará daño en el futuro.
Take out the token I gave you.
Saca el regalo que te di,
The Chiyan Stone.
la Piedra Ardiente.
It's here.
Aquí está, aquí está.
Here.
Aquí está.
You gave the Zhurong Stone to an outsider?
¡Le diste la Piedra Zhurong a una extraña!
This is the Zhurong Stone?
¿Es la Piedra Zhu... Zhurong?
Watch out!
¡Cuidado!
Go!
¡Vete!
Take care!
Ten cuidado.
Tongzhou,
Tongzhou,
you dare raise a hand against me?
¿te atreves a atacarme?
Calm your anger.
Tío, cálmese.
Lifei is no outsider.
Lifei no es una extraña.
She is my cultivation partner who shares life and death with me.
Es mi novia, con quien comparto vida y muerte.
Please grant us your permission.
Le pido que nos bendiga.
[Guangsheng Faction] We're finally out.
[Sociedad Guangsheng] Por fin salimos. Vámonos.
Hurry up!
Rápido, rápido.
Mere petty trickery.
Trucos baratos.
Reveal your form!
¡Muéstrate!
Over there! Chase!
¡Por allí. Persigan!
Yes!
Sí.
They're somewhere nearby.
Están cerca.
Mr. Luo,
Sr. Luo,
monster beasts
hay bestias.
are trying to kill me.
¡Hay una bestia que quiere matarme!
Where
¿Bestia?
are they?
¿Dónde está?
Over there!
Por allá.
There's evil spiritual energy
Tienes
all over you.
aura de bestia espiritual encima.
I must have gotten monster blood on myself
Quizá me manché con sangre de bestia
while fighting them earlier.
cuando luchaba contra ellos.
Master,
Maestro,
monster beasts are over there!
allí hay bestias.
Right there, let's check it out.
- Allá. - A ver.
- Go. - Chase!
- Vamos. - A perseguirlos.
Dawn is breaking soon.
Está amaneciendo.
Are you sure we can get out this way?
¿Estás seguro de que se puede salir por aquí?
There is a secret door under the jar fortress.
La Secta Wanxian tiene una salida secreta junto al muro.
We'll make it out for sure.
Seguro que podemos salir.
Leave it to me.
Déjame hacerlo.
This aura...
Este aura...
Jiang Lifei.
¡Jiang Lifei!
Let them pass.
Déjenlos pasar.
The trip is dangerous.
El viaje es peligroso.
Take care.
Cuídate.
Will do.
Bien.
Hurry!
Rápido.
What's going on here?
¿Qué pasó aquí?
What happened?
¿Qué está pasando?
I let my guard down.
Fui descuidado.
They mean to hunt us all down,
Quieren exterminarnos
leaving none alive.
a todos.
Fire! Look, there's fire!
¡Fuego, miren, hay fuego!
Fire!
¡Fuego!
Everyone, stay calm.
¡No entren en pánico, todos!
Mr. Lu,
Líder.
we signed a spirit pact
Hicimos un pacto espiritual
to live in peace alongside humans.
de convivir en paz con los humanos, ¿no?
Why do they seek to slay us,
¿Por qué nos matan
even leaving our bodies unburied?
y no nos dejan ni los huesos?
The formation won't hold much longer. What to do?
La formación se va a romper. ¿Qué hacemos?
I'll hold them off.
Yo aguanto.
Lead everyone away with Lu Li.
Tú y Lu Li lleven a los demás.
I'm staying here with you.
Yo me quedo contigo.
Lifei.
¡Lifei!
Don't you act on your own.
No hagas nada por tu cuenta.
The Fragrance Bond still binds us.
El Hechizo de Fragancia Eterna sigue ahí.
We swore
Lo prometimos,
to live and die together, never to abandon each other.
vivir o morir juntos, sin separarnos.
Neither of us shall break that.
Nadie puede faltar a su palabra.
[Riyan, Nine-Tailed Fox] It's so hot in here.
¡Qué calor!
What are you roasting?
¿Qué están asando ahora?
Riyan, you've healed up.
Riyan, ¿te recuperaste?
Please,
Te ruego,
let us get out of here.
déjanos salir.
I'll give it a shot.
Lo intentaré.
It's the mountain-sea barrier.
Es la Barrera de Montañas y Mares.
I can't break through.
No podemos pasar.
The old monster is here too.
Ese viejo también vino.
Wait for me!
Espérame.
Just listen to me.
Escúchame.
Don't touch me.
No me toques.
Riyan.
Estimado Riyan.
Riyan,
Su Excelencia.
could you teach me
¿Puedes enseñarme
the Divine Brush Teleportation skill?
ese truco de traslado instantáneo con el pincel?
Old monster, mind your own business!
Viejo, te metes donde no te llaman.
You're stealing my spotlight!
Me robaste el protagonismo.
Fox, you're truly ungrateful.
Zorro, qué mal educado.
I went out of my way to help you,
Te ayudo de buena fe
yet you won't even say thank you.
y ni siquiera me das las gracias.
Mr. Yan.
Sr. Yan.
Lifei,
Lifei,
we're fated to cross paths from afar.
tenemos este destino de encontrarnos desde lejos.
It'd be such a waste not to strike it rich together.
Sería una pena no hacer negocios juntos.
You stinky old monster!
Maldito.
Mr. Yan,
Sr. Yan,
what are you doing here?
¿qué haces aquí?
Lately, folks are on edge,
Últimamente la gente está inquieta
and business has been slow,
y los negocios van mal.
so I plan to travel overseas
Quiero viajar por ultramar
to gather material for new tales.
para buscar material para mis nuevas historias.
Mr. Yan,
Señor,
are you also a monster?
¿acaso usted también es una bestia espiritual?
Anything abnormal is labeled as a monster.
Para la gente, todo lo anormal es bestia.
In that sense,
Así que, en ese sentido,
we're all monsters.
todos somos bestias.
True.
¡Exacto!
None of us fit the norm,
Todos somos anormales.
so we're all monsters alike.
Todos somos bestias espirituales.
Mr. Yan,
Señor,
what kind of monster are you?
¿qué clase de bestia espiritual eres?
Your mastery over script spirit is peerless,
Su dominio de los espíritus del libro es impresionante.
so you must possess a semi-immortal body,
Debe ser un semi-inmortal
knowing all under heaven.
que sabe todo lo que pasa en el mundo.
Does that mean
Entonces,
all script spirits obey your will?
¿los espíritus del libro te obedecen?
No wonder you're skilled at spinning tales.
Por eso se le da bien inventar historias.
I'm deeply grateful to all of you for your help.
Maestro, gracias a todos por su ayuda.
I'll lead my clansmen to Yingcui Island to settle down.
Voy a llevar a mi gente a la isla Yingcui.
Farewell for now.
Nos despedimos.
Yingcui Island belongs to that great bird.
¿La isla Yingcui es territorio de ese gran pájaro?
Are you its descendant?
¿Tú eres descendiente de ese pájaro?
I'm Lu Li, leader of the Jiufeng Clan,
Soy el líder del Clan de Noveno Fénix.
half-monster.
Me llamo Lu Li, medio humano medio bestia.
Yingcui Island is thousands of miles away.
La isla Yingcui está lejos
You'll struggle to travel there.
y les cuesta viajar tanto.
I'll give you a ride.
Mejor los llevo yo.
Thanks, Mr. Yan.
Gracias, maestro.
Old coot,
Riyan,
you're tagging along.
tienes que venir conmigo.
I'm going overseas to find answers.
Necesito encontrar respuestas en ultramar.
Young man,
Mocoso,
come over here.
ven aquí.
I need a word with you.
Tengo que hablar contigo.
You've got your old memories back,
Ya que recuperaste tus recuerdos,
so you know who she is, right?
sabes quién es ella, ¿verdad?
So what if I know?
¿Y qué?
I've only ever wanted her
Desde el principio,
from day one.
solo quiero a ella.
Can you protect her?
¿Tienes la capacidad de protegerla?
You just want to
Lo que quieres
lock her up for yourself.
es tenerla como tu posesión.
Your so-called love
Engañarla con tu amor
is poisoning her.
solo la estás perjudicando.
Things will be different in this life.
Esta vida será diferente.
She might believe you
Una vez, dos veces,
a few times,
ella puede confiar en ti.
but she'll see through you eventually.
Pero llegará un día en que despierte ella.
Riyan,
Riyan,
you misunderstand her.
creo que se equivoca.
Lifei is far from foolish.
Lifei no es tonta,
At times,
a veces incluso
she is even wiser than I am
es más lista que yo.
and is clear about her choices.
Sabe lo que elige.
Mark my words.
Escúchame bien.
If she suffers even the slightest injury,
Si le falta un solo pelo,
I will hold you accountable.
te lo cobraré todo.
Rest assured.
Tranquilo, Riyan.
I'll protect her with all I have.
Yo la protegeré.
What are you two whispering about?
¿Qué están cuchicheando?
You don't want to leave me?
Te da pena dejarme, ¿verdad?
When I first met you,
La primera vez que te vi,
you were a fool.
eras una tonta.
Now that I'm leaving,
Ahora que me voy,
you still are.
sigues igual.
Just say it if you'll miss me.
Si me extrañas, dilo bien.
Enough,
Ya.
old fox.
Viejo zorro.
Let's go.
Vamos ya.
Young folks have their own paths to walk.
Los jóvenes tienen sus cosas.
Let's stay out of this.
Nosotros no nos metamos.
True.
Bien.
I've slept far too long.
Dormí demasiado.
Time to stretch my limbs.
Es hora de moverme las piernas.
Girl,
Chica,
on your way back,
cuando vuelvas,
visit the East Sea's cliff inscriptions.
pasarás por la Inscripción Rupestre en el Mar del Este.
Did you leave a treasure for me?
¿Me dejaste un tesoro?
I wonder if Lifei managed to escape.
No sé si Lifei logró escapar.
Don't worry.
Tranquila.
She'll be fine
Xiuyuan está con ella.
with Xiuyuan by her side.
No pasará nada grave.
Jiao said a witness
Jiao me dijo
claimed Lifei helped the monster clan run off.
que alguien acusó a Lifei de ayudar a las bestias a escapar.
We promised we wouldn't...
No dijimos que no...
We promised we wouldn't leave any clues.
No dijimos que no nos íbamos a delatar.
Who ratted them out?
¿Quién fue?
No matter who it is,
No importa quién sea,
Lifei will be in trouble if she comes back.
si Lifei vuelve, corre peligro.
Then she'd better stay away
Entonces que no vuelva.
and lie low somewhere.
Que se esconda un tiempo.
I'll go and find her.
Voy a buscarla.
Our trip begins at Mount Man by the East Sea.
El viaje comienza en la Montaña Man del Mar del Este.
Boundless ocean spreads out.
El océano es infinito.
By Qingcheng of Wuyue Court
Qingcheng, Secta Wuyueting.
and Riyan of Qingqiu.
Riyan de Qingqiu. Los dos dejaron el recado.
Riyan was actually close with Elder Qingcheng.
¿Riyan es amigo del maestro Qingcheng?
I never heard this before.
¿Tuvo esa historia?
Where do you reckon Elder Qingcheng ended up later?
¿Sabes adónde se fue el maestro Qingcheng?
My master said
Según mi maestro,
he invented the Five Turtle Technique.
él creó la Técnica de las Cinco Tortugas.
It's late.
Ya es tarde.
Let's go home.
Volvamos.
I figured Riyan might've felt guilty
Pensé que Riyan había recuperado su conciencia
and left me a spirit artifact.
y me había dejado algún tesoro.
Total letdown.
¡Qué poco confiable!
Xiuyuan,
Xiuyuan,
why'd you stick around?
¿por qué te quedaste?
Because you stayed.
Porque tú te quedaste.
You could've gone your separate way.
Pero podrías seguir tu propio camino.
After all,
Porque...
we can't stay together forever.
no podríamos estar juntos para siempre.
Why can't we?
¿Por qué no?
Our bond won't fade.
Mientras la Fragancia Eterna no se apague,
We won't leave each other, living or dead.
ni la muerte nos separará.
Lifei,
Lifei,
I want to be with you forever,
quiero estar siempre contigo.
in this lifetime,
En esta vida
and every next one.
y para siempre.
What're you talking about?
¿De qué hablan?
Nothing much.
Nada.
What brings you here?
¿Cómo es que viniste?
They say you worked with the monster clan
Alguien te acusó de ayudar
and broke them out of prison.
a las bestias a escapar.
Don't head back to Duanming City.
No puedes volver a la Ciudad Duanming.
I covered our tracks the whole trip.
No dejamos rastro en el camino.
Who ratted her out?
¿Quién nos acusó?
No clue.
No sé.
The elders plan
Los maestros
to question Lifei severely.
decidieron interrogar a Lifei.
This is bad.
Ya que estamos así,
Hide out with me at Xingzheng Hall for now.
ven conmigo al Pabellón Xingzheng a esconderte.
Running off now
Si me voy ahora,
would make me look guilty on the run.
eso sería huir por culpabilidad.
I didn't slip up at all last night.
Anoche no dejé ninguna prueba.
I'll just deny it.
Si niego todo, no pueden hacerme nada.
It won't be easy to get away with.
Lo ves demasiado simple.
Cuixuan and my uncle
Cuixuan y mi tío
will see right through our lies.
no se dejarán engañar fácilmente.
What if they torture you to talk?
¿Y si usan tortura?
They wouldn't do that.
No es para tanto.
Those sect elders
Son maestros de las sectas,
torture a weak girl
contra una discípula indefensa,
to get a fake confession?
usando tortura para hacerme confesar.
That's cruel.
Eso sería demasiado cruel.
And it'll be very embarrassing
Si se llega a saber,
if everyone finds out.
sería vergonzoso.
But what if they do?
¿Y si pasa?
We'll team up
Nosotros tres juntos,
and get through anything.
podemos superar todo.
I hunted monster beasts all night
Pasé toda la noche atrapando bestias,
and did my job properly.
haciendo mi trabajo muy responsable,
How do I suddenly become a demon spy?
¿cómo que soy espía?
Mr. Luo,
Sr. Luo,
we met last night, didn't we?
nos encontramos anoche, ¿recuerda?
I saw you last night,
Sí, te vi anoche.
but you reeked
Pero en ese momento
of evil spiritual energy back then.
tenías aura de bestia encima.
That just means
Eso prueba que
I was fighting monster beasts hard.
estuve luchando con bestias espirituales.
Lifei stuck with the group
Anoche, después de que Lifei se reunió conmigo,
and hunted monster beasts
estuvo persiguiendo bestias
straight through till morning.
hasta el amanecer.
You two have long been close friends.
Ustedes son amigos,
You might be lying
es posible que
to cover for one another.
se encubran mutuamente.
Qin,
Qin.
you mean we're covering each other,
¿Quieres decir que nos encubrimos mutuamente?
and that makes me a spy, too?
¿Que yo también soy espía?
I followed the evil spiritual energy last night
Anoche seguí el rastro de aura de bestia espiritual
and was jumped halfway.
y alguien me atacó por la espalda.
Jiang Lifei's the one
Esa persona
who attacked me.
fue Jiang Lifei.
Qin,
Qin.
you've hated me ever since what happened
Sé que desde lo del Valle Lilie
at Lilie Valley.
me guardas rencor.
If you want to get even,
Si quieres vengarte,
fight me fair and square.
peleemos de verdad.
Quit stabbing me in the back.
No hagas estas cosas sucias a escondidas.
You're disgracing Wuyue Court
Desprestigiaste a la Secta Wuyueting
and Elder Cuixuan.
y al maestro Cuixuan.
You!
¡Tú!
Yangling,
Yangling,
you said she attacked you.
dices que quien te atacó fue Jiang Lifei.
Got any evidence?
¿Tienes pruebas?
I'm sure
Estoy seguro de que
that energy is definitely hers.
ese aura era de Jiang Lifei.
Qin,
Qin.
I didn't know
No esperaba que
you thought about me so much
estuvieras tan obsesionado conmigo,
that you see me
que aún me tuvieras presente
in everyone now.
y que vieras a todos como a mí.
She's the demon spy.
¡Ella es espía demoníaca!
It's her!
¡Es ella!
She dressed up like one of us from the Wanxian Sect
Vestida como nosotros, de la Secta Wanxian
and knocked us out with drugs.
y nos drogó con veneno.
Did you actually see me drug you?
¿Me viste poner el veneno?
No, we didn't.
No, no lo vi.
But right after you walked past,
Pero cuando pasaste,
we passed out.
nos desmayamos.
You were all lazing around
Ustedes se durmieron,
and sleeping on duty.
descuidaron la vigilancia
That's why the monster beasts got away.
y dejaron escapar a las bestias.
Now
¿Qué?
you're scared of taking the blame,
¿No asumen la culpa
so you lie and pin it on me?
y la echan a otros?
Well... I...
Esto...
Speaking of which,
Dicho esto,
you really did have
esa noche vestías
our Wanxian Sect outer robe on that night.
la túnica de la Secta Wanxian.
Why was that?
¿Por qué?
This is all on me.
Eso es culpa mía.
Lifei only took
Lifei fue a buscar a mi tío
such a risky action to visit
y recurrió a este plan
my uncle for my sake.
por mi culpa.
You're from Wuyue Court.
Una discípula de la Secta Wuyueting,
What were you doing
en plena noche,
visiting Mr. Xuanshan late at night?
¿por qué fue a ver al Sr. Xuanshan?
I wanted to form a cultivation partnership with Lifei,
Quiero cultivar junto a Lifei como pareja.
but I feared that my uncle wouldn't agree.
Temía que no lo aceptara.
She panicked
Lifei se preocupó
and went straight in to ask why.
y quiso ir a preguntarle.
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[Fragancia Eterna]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪Llevo conmigo la lujuria del mundo mortal♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪A cambio de unos instantes contigo♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪Nuestros destinos están entrelazados, nos abrazamos y combatimos mutuamente♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪Es difícil de equilibrar♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪Luchamos cegados, miles de caminos brotan en el corazón♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪El amor vuelve a germinar en esta vida♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪Ni mil catástrofes superan el hilo de fragancia que nos une♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪Te acompaño cuando las montañas se derrumben y los mares se vuelvan arena♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪Cuando las ramas secas florezcan flores♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪Caminemos juntos al Puente del Olvido♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪Torres budistas, caballos con ropas brillantes♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪Siempre al final de cada obsesión♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪Ese instante en que el corazón se ablanda♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪Aunque todos me abandonen, no temo luchar♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪Me transformo junto a ti♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪Piso las nubes, miles de nubes coloridas están bajo mis pies♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪A cambio de unos instantes contigo♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪Miles de flechas atraviesan mi corazón, dolores y enfermedades se acumulan♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪Pero guardo silencio♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪Amor profundo y pensamientos largos, los besos caen sobre la cama en sueños♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪En las noches lejanas, las flores brotan del sufrimiento♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪Reconstruyo capítulos gloriosos para asombrar los ocho reinos♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪Te acompaño cuando las montañas se derrumben y los mares se vuelvan arena♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪Cuando las ramas secas florezcan flores♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪Caminemos juntos al Puente del Olvido♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪Torres budistas, caballos con ropas brillantes♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪Siempre al final de cada obsesión♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪Ese instante en que el corazón se ablanda♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪Aunque todos me abandonen, no temo luchar♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪Si el sello no se puede romper, déjalo estar♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪El lugar donde el corazón descansa es mi hogar♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪Volar uno a lado del otro entre las nubes♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪Romper las olas, un mar infinito en el corazón♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪Siempre al final del destino♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪Ese instante en que me mantengo firme♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪El cielo y la tierra son como flores caídas♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪Dejo que toda mi vida pase sin importarme♪